<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>CoastCompanion Blog</title>
        <link>https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog</link>
        <description>CoastCompanion Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet The Backbencher - Dabin]]></title>
            <link>https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/dabin</link>
            <guid>https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/dabin</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Dabin Picture]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/112664372?v=4" alt="Dabin Picture" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<p>Meet <strong>Dabin</strong>, a driven student at the University of British Columbia, immersed in the world of Computer Science. Within the highly specialized members of The Backbenchers, he stands as the most versatile and ingenuous. As one of the group's adept full-stack engineers, Dabin's work extends across various domains, from front-end implementations to back-end functionalities.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="dabins-background">Dabin's Background<a href="https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/dabin#dabins-background" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Dabin's Background" title="Direct link to Dabin's Background">​</a></h2>
<p>What sets Dabin apart is not just his technical proficiency, but his ability to navigate complex software landscapes despite being a newcomer to large-scale project development. Unlike many other members, Dabin's journey into the realm of software engineering hasn't been paved with industry internships or co-op terms. Yet, his lack of traditional experience hasn't hindered his ability to make significant contributions to the team. In fact, Dabin has made contributions consisting of the widest range of tasks we had building Coast Companion.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="dabins-full-stack-role-in-the-backbenchers">Dabin's Full-Stack Role in The Backbenchers<a href="https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/dabin#dabins-full-stack-role-in-the-backbenchers" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Dabin's Full-Stack Role in The Backbenchers" title="Direct link to Dabin's Full-Stack Role in The Backbenchers">​</a></h2>
<p>At the heart of Dabin's role within The Backbenchers lies his keen eye for optimization and his relentless pursuit of synchronicity between frontend and backend systems. He thrives on the challenge of identifying database design enhancements, resolving bugs, and, perhaps most crucially, ensuring seamless integration between different layers of the software architecture.</p>
<p>In frontend development, Dabin's expertise shines brightly, particularly in his implementation of the Chat Sessions page within the Admin Panel. On the backend, Dabin's domain is the implementation of lambda functions—key components of our AWS tech stack that power the essential API interactions necessary for the Admin Panel's smooth operation.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="dabins-future-and-goals-to-success">Dabin's Future and Goals to Success<a href="https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/dabin#dabins-future-and-goals-to-success" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Dabin's Future and Goals to Success" title="Direct link to Dabin's Future and Goals to Success">​</a></h2>
<p>Beyond his technical acumen, Dabin embodies the spirit of continuous growth and exploration. With an eye toward the future, he eagerly seeks opportunities to expand his horizons, including the pursuit of co-op positions to further refine his skills and broaden his industry insights.</p>
<p>For the upcoming summer, Dabin plans on building doing another software engineering project to refine his skills he learend from building Coast Capital with The Backbenchers.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>team</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meet The Backbencher - Matthew]]></title>
            <link>https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/matthew</link>
            <guid>https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/matthew</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Allow me to introduce you to Matthew (he/him/his), a dedicated 4th-year Computer Science student at the University of British Columbia. Matthew is one of the last Backbencher to join the team, and is one of the only Backbenchers to focus soley on frontend and user experience.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Allow me to introduce you to <strong>Matthew</strong> (<em>he/him/his</em>), a dedicated 4th-year Computer Science student at the University of British Columbia. Matthew is one of the last Backbencher to join the team, and is <strong>one of the only Backbenchers to focus soley on frontend and user experience</strong>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="backend-focused-background">Backend-Focused Background<a href="https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/matthew#backend-focused-background" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Backend-Focused Background" title="Direct link to Backend-Focused Background">​</a></h2>
<p>Matthew's journey into frontend development began with a surprising twist, considering his prior experience with frontend was limited to just building non-framework static <code>html</code>, <code>css</code>, and <code>js</code> pages for backend-focused projects. However, his knack for problem-solving and dedication to writing quality code proved invaluable as he embarked on this new venture.</p>
<p>Before joining The Backbenchers, Matthew's had a co-op term with the BC Provincial Health Services Authority (PHSA), where he honed his skills in managing healthcare information systems. His responsibilities included improving mass-data healthcare information systems, streamlining workflow processes within managing multiple systems, analyzing existing systems across regional health authorities, and synthesizing and querying individualized data in the healthcare database into comprehensive statistics—a testament to his proficiency in navigating complex datasets.</p>
<p>Additionally, since 2020, Matthew is also working as a Teaching Assistant for UBC's major stream introductory Computer Science course, CPSC 110, which focuses on program design (i.e. writing <em>quality</em> code) and heavily emphasizes the idea: <em>"Code that works properly is not nearly good enough"</em>. Code needs to follow a consistent strucutre, a design, that is most appropreate for the domain we work under.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="admin-panel-development--api-design">Admin Panel Development &amp; API Design<a href="https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/matthew#admin-panel-development--api-design" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Admin Panel Development &amp; API Design" title="Direct link to Admin Panel Development &amp; API Design">​</a></h2>
<p>Matthew's pivotal role in the development of the Admin Panel came to the forefront following the mid-term demo, where the team collectively decided to overhaul the existing interface. Drawing from his extensive experience in healthcare information systems, Matthew spearheaded the redesign efforts, focusing on enhancing usability for Coast Companion analysts.</p>
<p>His expertise extended to crafting a new Figma prototype, refining page layouts, implementing crucial functionalities, and devising a well-formed <strong>API design with extensive and clear documentation</strong>. Matthew's approach to API design was underscored by his commitment to clarity and precision, as seen thorough his documentation outlining problem domains, edge cases, and input/output types. This structured framework empowered the backend team to focus on implementation, free from ambiguities or inconsistencies and functional design choices.</p>
<p>Matthew has additionally taken the initiative to establish comprehensive style guidelines for the Admin Panel frontend, drawing inspiration from industry-leading practices observed in similar React projects. The guide aims to cultivate a culture of consistency, readability, maintainability within the Backbenchers team, fostering a collaborative environment where code quality is taken as a priority.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="bonus-project-demo-page">Bonus Project: Demo Page<a href="https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/matthew#bonus-project-demo-page" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Bonus Project: Demo Page" title="Direct link to Bonus Project: Demo Page">​</a></h2>
<p>Matthew also undertook the creation of the Demo Page—an essential hub housing links to our demo and final product, release notes, documentation, team information, and even this very blog post introducing Matthew! Docusaurus, a static site generator often used for building documentation websites, was used for this. Matthew authored a comprehensive guide to Docusaurus, tailored specifically for The Backbenchers. This can be read <a href="https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/guide/">here</a>.</p>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="matthews-future-plans">Matthew's Future Plans<a href="https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/matthew#matthews-future-plans" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Matthew's Future Plans" title="Direct link to Matthew's Future Plans">​</a></h2>
<p>Matthew has gained invaluable experience through his contributions to Coast Companion, and he is thankful for the department and Coast Capital for giving him the oppertunity to work on frontend—an area he had never previously considered exploring.</p>
<p>Following this invaluable expereince, Matthew plans on <em>possibly</em> doing another co-op job in the fall of this year, and hopes to join a full-stack software development team and make great contributions.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>team</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Work In Progress 1]]></title>
            <link>https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/wip-1</link>
            <guid>https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/wip-1</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[As we embark on this exciting journey to create Coast Companion, it's essential to note that the details presented here are part of our ongoing work in progress report. Our team, the Backbenchers, is currently in the early stages of development, and this introduction serves as a snapshot of our initial objectives and commitment. As we delve deeper into the project, this report will provide a comprehensive overview of our progress, challenges faced, and the innovative solutions we implement. We appreciate the opportunity to share our journey with you and look forward to updating you on the evolution of Coast Companion.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As we embark on this exciting journey to create Coast Companion, it's essential to note that the details presented here are part of our ongoing work in progress report. Our team, the Backbenchers, is currently in the early stages of development, and this introduction serves as a snapshot of our initial objectives and commitment. As we delve deeper into the project, this report will provide a comprehensive overview of our progress, challenges faced, and the innovative solutions we implement. We appreciate the opportunity to share our journey with you and look forward to updating you on the evolution of Coast Companion.</p>
<p>Here is the demo link for our application: <a href="https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo</a></p>
<p>We made some progress but we were set back by our AWS setup issues, we were pushed back 1 to 2 weeks behind expected development progress</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="we-aimed-to-achieve-the-following-goals">We aimed to achieve the following goals:<a href="https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/wip-1#we-aimed-to-achieve-the-following-goals" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to We aimed to achieve the following goals:" title="Direct link to We aimed to achieve the following goals:">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Interface for Chatbot Interaction: The user interface should have a text box to send questions to the chatbot and receive answers.</li>
<li>Interface to Provide Feedback for Chatbot’s Answers: After the chatbot answers a question, it should offer users an opportunity to give feedback on the chatbot's response. These responses will help fine-tune future responses to similar queries.</li>
<li>Interface to Add/Remove/Update the Chatbot Information: The chatbot's answers should be capable of being changed by editing prompts.</li>
<li>Interface to see Chatbot’s Performance: User’s response rating, chatbot’s response times, and user satisfaction should be viewable to show the chatbot's performance and viability.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="our-progress-on-our-goals">Our Progress on our Goals<a href="https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/wip-1#our-progress-on-our-goals" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Our Progress on our Goals" title="Direct link to Our Progress on our Goals">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Interface for Chatbot Interaction: This is complete and you can easily put a script tag on any website to add Coast Companion to your website.</li>
<li>Interface to Provide Feedback for Chatbot’s Answers: This is incomplete. While we have the administrative dashboard to see performance metrics on the Chatbot, we are still unable to deliver feedback to the chatbot immediately.</li>
<li>Interface to Add/Remove/Update the Chatbot Information: This is incomplete. The interface is ready to be used but still needs to be connected to the backend.</li>
<li>Interface to see Chatbot’s Performance: This is incomplete. The interface is ready but still needs to be connected to the backend.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="difficulties-we-faced">Difficulties We Faced<a href="https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/wip-1#difficulties-we-faced" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Difficulties We Faced" title="Direct link to Difficulties We Faced">​</a></h3>
<p>We encountered technical difficulties setting up the project and building our first iteration.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>AWS Permissions Blockers:</strong> Issues with AWS permissions emerged as significant blockers, demanding meticulous attention to detail and troubleshooting to ensure a smooth project progression.</li>
<li><strong>Lex Limitation:</strong> Initially considered for integration, Lex was found to lack Language Model capabilities, prompting us to reconsider and adjust our technology stack accordingly.</li>
<li><strong>Kendra Cost Concerns:</strong> Implementation of Kendra, a potential solution, proved more expensive than anticipated, necessitating a reassessment of budgetary considerations and exploration of cost-effective alternatives.</li>
</ul>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="deviations">Deviations<a href="https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/wip-1#deviations" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Deviations" title="Direct link to Deviations">​</a></h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Deviations in Technology Stack:</strong> In the development of Coast Companion, we opted for deviations from the initially considered LLama2 or Lex/Kendra solutions.</li>
<li><strong>Claude Embedding Model Integration:</strong> Instead of the initially planned options, we chose to utilize the Claude embedding model. This decision was made based on its suitability for our specific project requirements and objectives.</li>
<li><strong>Model Agent Integration:</strong> To seamlessly integrate various embedding models with our Language Model (LLM), we implemented a model agent. This agent serves as the glue that binds different embedding models together, ensuring cohesive functionality and optimal performance within Coast Companion.</li>
</ul>
<h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="our-next-steps">Our Next Steps<a href="https://thed3vel0per.github.io/CoastCompanionDemo/blog/wip-1#our-next-steps" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Our Next Steps" title="Direct link to Our Next Steps">​</a></h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Bug Fixes:</strong> Conduct thorough testing and debugging to identify and resolve any existing bugs or issues within the system.</li>
<li><strong>Finish Backend Linking for Admin Panel:</strong> Complete the backend integration for the Admin Panel to ensure seamless functionality and accessibility for administrative tasks.</li>
<li><strong>Implement Rating Delivery Mechanism:</strong> Develop and implement the frontend components required for the rating feature, ensuring a user-friendly interface and experience.</li>
<li><strong>Lower Response Time:</strong> Conduct performance analysis and implement optimizations to lower response time, enhancing the overall user experience and ensuring Coast Companion operates with optimal efficiency. Evaluate and refine both backend and frontend components to achieve a more responsive system.</li>
<li><strong>Add Citations to Chatbot:</strong> Enhance the credibility of Coast Companion by implementing a citation display feature in the chatbot responses. This addition ensures transparency and allows users to view the sources of information, promoting trust and reliability in the information provided by the chatbot.</li>
</ul>
<p>Looking foward for more progress! <br>
<strong>The Backbenchers</strong></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>WIP</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>